<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Certificate on Abdulrahman Alomairah</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/certificate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Certificate on Abdulrahman Alomairah</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 22:22:41 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/certificate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to eJPTv2 Certification</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/ejptv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 22:22:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/ejptv2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.accredible.com/v1/frontend/credential_website_embed_image/certificate/81589719&#34; alt=&#34;eJPTv2 Certification&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a fascination with penetration testing, information gathering, and enumeration. There&amp;rsquo;s something thrilling about delving into the intricacies of a system, discovering its vulnerabilities, and ultimately strengthening its defenses. But for me, it&amp;rsquo;s more than just a passion; it&amp;rsquo;s a way of life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;embracing-control-and-privacy&#34;&gt;Embracing Control and Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the driving forces behind my interest in penetration testing is my love for self-hosting personal services. I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in having control over my data and privacy. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s my email server, cloud storage, or even my personal website, I prefer to manage these services myself. It allows me to ensure that my data remains mine and is not at the mercy of third-party providers. &lt;em&gt;Most of the time&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STC Incident Response Virtual Work Experiance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/stc_incidentresponse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 11:44:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/stc_incidentresponse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;certificate-of-completion-virtual-work-experience-in-cybersecurity-incident-response-analysis&#34;&gt;Certificate of Completion: Virtual Work Experience in Cybersecurity Incident Response Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share that I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully completed a Virtual Work Experience program focused on &lt;strong&gt;Cybersecurity Incident Response Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;. This immersive program provided me with invaluable insights into the world of cybersecurity and equipped me with practical skills to effectively respond to potential threats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;program-highlights&#34;&gt;Program Highlights:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hands-on Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; Throughout the program, I had the opportunity to work with real-world data and scenarios. This allowed me to gain practical experience and a deeper understanding of cyber threats and vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
